[["Elon Musk, the CEO of SpaceX, announced that the company plans to send the first humans to Mars by 2024. This announcement was made during a press conference at the Kennedy Space Center in Florida on July 20, 2023. SpaceX, headquartered in Hawthorne, California, has been at the forefront of space exploration since its founding in 2002. Musk, a billionaire entrepreneur, also co-founded Tesla, Inc., which is known for its electric vehicles.\n\nOn the political front, President Joe Biden signed a new climate bill into law on August 15, 2023, in Washington, D.C. The bill aims to reduce carbon emissions by 40% by the year 2030. The signing ceremony was attended by several prominent senators, including Chuck Schumer and Elizabeth Warren. The bill has been hailed as a significant step towards addressing global warming.\n\nIn the world of sports, Serena Williams announced her retirement from professional tennis on September 1, 2023. Williams, who has won 23 Grand Slam singles titles, made the announcement during an emotional interview with Oprah Winfrey. Her retirement marks the end of an era in women's tennis, where she dominated the sport for nearly two decades.\n\nThe tech giant Apple Inc. unveiled its latest iPhone model, the iPhone 15, on September 12, 2023, at its headquarters in Cupertino, California. The new model features several groundbreaking technologies, including a foldable screen and enhanced AI capabilities. Apple's CEO, Tim Cook, stated that the iPhone 15 is the most advanced smartphone ever created.\n\nIn financial news, the stock market experienced significant volatility in the second quarter of 2023. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell by 10% due to concerns over rising inflation and interest rates. However, tech stocks such as Amazon, Google, and Microsoft saw gains as investors flocked to companies with strong growth potential.\n\nOn the international stage, the United Nations held its annual General Assembly meeting in New York City from September 19-23, 2023. World leaders discussed critical issues such as climate change, global health, and geopolitical tensions. Notable speakers included the Secretary-General António Guterres, French President Emmanuel Macron, and Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi.\n\nIn the entertainment industry, the 95th Academy Awards took place on March 27, 2023, in Los Angeles, California. The event was hosted by comedian Kevin Hart and featured performances by several renowned artists. The Best Picture award was won by the film \"The Power of the Dog,\" directed by Jane Campion. Actress Zendaya won the Best Actress award for her role in the film \"Dune.\"\n\nIn scientific developments, researchers at MIT announced a breakthrough in quantum computing on June 10, 2023. The team, led by Dr. Alice Johnson, developed a new quantum processor that can perform complex calculations at unprecedented speeds. This advancement is expected to revolutionize fields such as cryptography and material science.\n\nMeanwhile, in the healthcare sector, Pfizer and BioNTech released data on their new COVID-19 vaccine booster on April 22, 2023. The booster has shown to be highly effective against the Omicron variant of the virus. The companies are seeking emergency use authorization from the FDA and expect the booster to be available to the public by the fall.\n\nLastly, in the realm of literature, celebrated author J.K. Rowling published her latest novel, \"The Silver Circle,\" on November 5, 2023. The book, a fantasy thriller, has already topped bestseller lists worldwide. Rowling, best known for the Harry Potter series, continues to captivate readers with her imaginative storytelling.\n", {"entities": [["Elon Musk", "PERSON"], ["first", "ORDINAL"], ["Mars", "LOC"], ["2024", "DATE"], ["the Kennedy Space Center", "FAC"], ["Florida", "GPE"], ["July 20, 2023", "DATE"], ["Hawthorne", "GPE"], ["California", "GPE"], ["2002", "DATE"], ["Tesla, Inc.", "ORG"], ["Joe Biden", "PERSON"], ["August 15, 2023", "DATE"], ["Washington", "GPE"], ["D.C.", "GPE"], ["40%", "PERCENT"], ["the year 2030", "DATE"], ["Chuck Schumer", "PERSON"], ["Elizabeth Warren", "PERSON"], ["Serena Williams", "PERSON"], ["September 1, 2023", "DATE"], ["Williams", "PERSON"], ["23", "CARDINAL"], ["Oprah Winfrey", "PERSON"], ["nearly two decades", "DATE"], ["Apple Inc.", "ORG"], ["September 12, 2023", "DATE"], ["Cupertino", "GPE"], ["California", "GPE"], ["AI", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Tim Cook", "PERSON"], ["the second quarter of 2023", "DATE"], ["10%", "PERCENT"], ["Amazon", "ORG"], ["Google", "ORG"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["the United Nations", "ORG"], ["General Assembly", "ORG"], ["New York City", "GPE"], ["September 19-23, 2023", "DATE"], ["António Guterres", "PERSON"], ["French", "NORP"], ["Emmanuel Macron", "PERSON"], ["Indian", "NORP"], ["Narendra Modi", "PERSON"], ["95th", "ORDINAL"], ["Academy Awards", "ORG"], ["March 27, 2023", "DATE"], ["Los Angeles", "GPE"], ["California", "GPE"], ["Kevin Hart", "PERSON"], ["The Power of the Dog", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["Jane Campion", "PERSON"], ["Actress Zendaya", "PERSON"], ["Dune", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["MIT", "ORG"], ["quantum", "ORG"], ["June 10, 2023", "DATE"], ["Alice Johnson", "PERSON"], ["quantum", "ORG"], ["Pfizer", "PERSON"], ["COVID-19", "ORG"], ["April 22, 2023", "DATE"], ["Omicron", "ORG"], ["FDA", "ORG"], ["J.K. Rowling", "PERSON"], ["The Silver Circle", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["November 5, 2023", "DATE"], ["Harry Potter", "PERSON"]]}], ["Microsoft Corporation is an American multinational corporation and technology company headquartered in Redmond, Washington.[2] Its best-known software products are the Windows line of operating systems, the Microsoft 365 suite of productivity applications, the Azure cloud computing platform and the Edge web browser. Its flagship hardware products are the Xbox video game consoles and the Microsoft Surface lineup of touchscreen personal computers. Microsoft ranked No. 14 in the 2022 Fortune 500 rankings of the largest United States corporations by total revenue;[3] and it was the world's largest software maker by revenue in 2022 according to Forbes Global 2000. It is considered one of the Big Five American information technology companies, alongside Alphabet (parent company of Google), Amazon, Apple, and Meta (parent company of Facebook).\n\nMicrosoft was founded by Bill Gates and Paul Allen on April 4, 1975, to develop and sell BASIC interpreters for the Altair 8800. It rose to dominate the personal computer operating system market with MS-DOS in the mid-1980s, followed by Windows. The company's 1986 initial public offering (IPO) and subsequent rise in its share price created three billionaires and an estimated 12,000 millionaires among Microsoft employees. Since the 1990s, it has increasingly diversified from the operating system market and has made several corporate acquisitions, the largest being the acquisition of Activision Blizzard for $68.7 billion in October 2023,[4] followed by its acquisition of LinkedIn for $26.2 billion in December 2016,[5] and its acquisition of Skype Technologies for $8.5 billion in May 2011.[6]\n\nAs of 2015, Microsoft is market-dominant in the IBM PC compatible operating system market and the office software suite market, although it has lost the majority of the overall operating system market to Android.[7] The company also produces a wide range of other consumer and enterprise software for desktops, laptops, tabs, gadgets, and servers, including Internet search (with Bing), the digital services market (through MSN), mixed reality (HoloLens), cloud computing (Azure), and software development (Visual Studio).\n\nSteve Ballmer replaced Gates as CEO in 2000 and later envisioned a \"devices and services\" strategy.[8] This unfolded with Microsoft acquiring Danger Inc. in 2008,[9] entering the personal computer production market for the first time in June 2012 with the launch of the Microsoft Surface line of tablet computers, and later forming Microsoft Mobile through the acquisition of Nokia's devices and services division. Since Satya Nadella took over as CEO in 2014, the company has scaled back on hardware and instead focused on cloud computing, a move that helped the company's shares reach their highest value since December 1999.[10][11] Under Nadella's direction, the company has also heavily expanded its gaming business to support the Xbox brand, establishing the Microsoft Gaming division in 2022, dedicated to operating Xbox in addition to its three subsidiaries (publishers). Microsoft Gaming is the third-largest gaming company in the world by revenue as of 2024.[12]\n\nIn 2018, Microsoft became the most valuable publicly traded company in the world, a position it has repeatedly traded with Apple in the years since.[13] In April 2019, Microsoft reached a trillion-dollar market cap, becoming the third U.S. public company to be valued at over $1 trillion after Apple and Amazon, respectively. As of 2024, Microsoft has the third-highest global brand valuation.\n\nMicrosoft has been criticized for its monopolistic practices and the company's software has been criticized for problems with ease of use, robustness, and security.\n\nMicrosoft is one of only two U.S.-based companies that has a prime credit rating of AAA.[14]", {"entities": [["Microsoft Corporation", "ORG"], ["American", "NORP"], ["Redmond", "GPE"], ["Windows", "NORP"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["Azure", "ORG"], ["Edge", "ORG"], ["Xbox", "ORG"], ["Microsoft Surface", "ORG"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["14", "CARDINAL"], ["2022", "DATE"], ["Fortune 500", "LAW"], ["United States", "GPE"], ["revenue;[3]", "PERSON"], ["2022", "DATE"], ["Forbes Global 2000", "ORG"], ["American", "NORP"], ["Alphabet", "GPE"], ["Google", "ORG"], ["Amazon", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Meta", "ORG"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["Bill Gates", "PERSON"], ["Paul Allen", "PERSON"], ["April 4, 1975", "DATE"], ["Altair", "PERSON"], ["MS-DOS", "ORG"], ["the mid-1980s", "DATE"], ["Windows", "ORG"], ["1986", "DATE"], ["IPO", "ORG"], ["three", "CARDINAL"], ["an estimated 12,000", "CARDINAL"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["the 1990s", "DATE"], ["Activision Blizzard", "PERSON"], ["$68.7 billion", "MONEY"], ["October", "DATE"], ["LinkedIn", "GPE"], ["$26.2 billion", "MONEY"], ["December 2016,[5", "DATE"], ["Skype Technologies", "ORG"], ["$8.5 billion", "MONEY"], ["May 2011.[6", "DATE"], ["2015", "DATE"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["IBM", "ORG"], ["Bing", "ORG"], ["MSN", "ORG"], ["HoloLens", "GPE"], ["Visual Studio", "PERSON"], ["Steve Ballmer", "PERSON"], ["Gates", "ORG"], ["2000", "DATE"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["Danger Inc.", "ORG"], ["2008,[9", "CARDINAL"], ["first", "ORDINAL"], ["June 2012", "DATE"], ["Microsoft Mobile", "ORG"], ["Nokia", "ORG"], ["Satya Nadella", "PERSON"], ["2014", "DATE"], ["December 1999.[10][11", "DATE"], ["Nadella", "PERSON"], ["Xbox", "PRODUCT"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["2022", "DATE"], ["Xbox", "PRODUCT"], ["three", "CARDINAL"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["2018", "DATE"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["the years", "DATE"], ["April 2019", "DATE"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["trillion-dollar", "MONEY"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["over $1 trillion", "MONEY"], ["Apple", "ORG"], ["Amazon", "ORG"], ["2024", "DATE"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["third", "ORDINAL"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["Microsoft", "ORG"], ["one", "CARDINAL"], ["only two", "CARDINAL"]]}], ["\"Expenses\" redirects here. For the Better Call Saul episode, see Expenses (Better Call Saul).\nAn expense is an item requiring an outflow of money, or any form of fortune in general, to another person or group as payment for an item, service, or other category of costs. For a tenant, rent is an expense. For students or parents, tuition is an expense. Buying food, clothing, furniture, or an automobile is often referred to as an expense. An expense is a cost that is \"paid\" or \"remitted\", usually in exchange for something of value. Something that seems to cost a great deal is \"expensive\". Something that seems to cost little is \"inexpensive\". \"Expenses of the table\" are expenses for dining, refreshments, a feast, etc.\n\nIn accounting, expense is any specific outflow of cash or other valuable assets from a person or company to another person or company. This outflow is generally one side of a trade for products or services that have equal or better current or future value to the buyer than to the seller. Technically, an expense is an event in which a proprietary stake is diminished or exhausted, or a liability is incurred. In terms of the accounting equation, expenses reduce owners' equity. The International Accounting Standards Board defines expenses as:\n...decreases in economic benefits during the accounting period in the form of outflows or depletions of assets or incurrences of liabilities that result in decreases in equity, other than those relating to distributions to equity participants.[1]\n\nExpense is a term also used in sociology, in which a particular fortune or price is sacrificed voluntarily or involuntarily by something or someone to something or somebody else, often in the context that the latter is taking advantage of the former.\n\nBookkeeping for expenses\nIn double-entry bookkeeping, expenses are recorded as a debit to an expense account (an income statement account) and a credit to either an asset account or a liability account, which are balance sheet accounts. An expense decreases assets or increases liabilities. Typical business expenses include salaries, utilities, depreciation of capital assets, and interest expense for loans. The purchase of a capital asset such as a building or equipment is not an expense.", {"entities": [["the Better Call Saul", "ORG"], ["Expenses (Better Call Saul", "ORG"], ["The International Accounting Standards Board", "ORG"]]}], ["Bookkeeping is the recording of financial transactions, and is part of the process of accounting in business and other organizations.[1] It involves preparing source documents for all transactions, operations, and other events of a business. Transactions include purchases, sales, receipts and payments by an individual person or an organization/corporation. There are several standard methods of bookkeeping, including the single-entry and double-entry bookkeeping systems. While these may be viewed as \"real\" bookkeeping, any process for recording financial transactions is a bookkeeping process.\n\nThe person in an organisation who is employed to perform bookkeeping functions is usually called the bookkeeper (or book-keeper). They usually write the daybooks (which contain records of sales, purchases, receipts, and payments), and document each financial transaction, whether cash or credit, into the correct daybook—that is, petty cash book, suppliers ledger, customer ledger, etc.—and the general ledger. Thereafter, an accountant can create financial reports from the information recorded by the bookkeeper. The bookkeeper brings the books to the trial balance stage, from which an accountant may prepare financial reports for the organisation, such as the income statement and balance sheet.\n\nHistory\nThe origin of book-keeping is lost in obscurity, but recent research indicates that methods of keeping accounts have existed from the remotest times of human life in cities. Babylonian records written with styli on small slabs of clay have been found dating to 2600 BC.[2] Mesopotamian bookkeepers kept records on clay tablets that may date back as far as 7,000 years. Use of the modern double entry bookkeeping system was described by Luca Pacioli in 1494.[3]\n\nThe term \"waste book\" was used in colonial America, referring to the documenting of daily transactions of receipts and expenditures. Records were made in chronological order, and for temporary use only. Daily records were then transferred to a daybook or account ledger to balance the accounts and to create a permanent journal; then the waste book could be discarded, hence the name.[4]\n\nProcess\nThe primary purpose of bookkeeping is to record the financial effects of transactions. An important difference between a manual and an electronic accounting system is the former's latency between the recording of a financial transaction and its posting in the relevant account. This delay, which is absent in electronic accounting systems due to nearly instantaneous posting to relevant accounts, is characteristic of manual systems, and gave rise to the primary books of accounts—cash book, purchase book, sales book, etc.—for immediately documenting a financial transaction.\n\nIn the normal course of business, a document is produced each time a transaction occurs. Sales and purchases usually have invoices or receipts. Historically, deposit slips were produced when lodgements (deposits) were made to a bank account; and checks (spelled \"cheques\" in the UK and several other countries) were written to pay money out of the account. Nowadays such transactions are mostly made electronically. Bookkeeping first involves recording the details of all of these source documents into multi-column journals (also known as books of first entry or daybooks). For example, all credit sales are recorded in the sales journal; all cash payments are recorded in the cash payments journal. Each column in a journal normally corresponds to an account. In the single entry system, each transaction is recorded only once. Most individuals who balance their check-book each month are using such a system, and most personal-finance software follows this approach.\n\nAfter a certain period, typically a month, each column in each journal is totalled to give a summary for that period. Using the rules of double-entry, these journal summaries are then transferred to their respective accounts in the ledger, or account book. For example, the entries in the Sales Journal are taken and a debit entry is made in each customer's account (showing that the customer now owes us money), and a credit entry might be made in the account for \"Sale of class 2 widgets\" (showing that this activity has generated revenue for us). This process of transferring summaries or individual transactions to the ledger is called posting. Once the posting process is complete, accounts kept using the \"T\" format (debits on the left side of the \"T\" and credits on the right side) undergo balancing, which is simply a process to arrive at the balance of the account.\n\nAs a partial check that the posting process was done correctly, a working document called an unadjusted trial balance is created. In its simplest form, this is a three-column list. Column One contains the names of those accounts in the ledger which have a non-zero balance. If an account has a debit balance, the balance amount is copied into Column Two (the debit column); if an account has a credit balance, the amount is copied into Column Three (the credit column). The debit column is then totalled, and then the credit column is totalled. The two totals must agree—which is not by chance—because under the double-entry rules, whenever there is a posting, the debits of the posting equal the credits of the posting. If the two totals do not agree, an error has been made, either in the journals or during the posting process. The error must be located and rectified, and the totals of the debit column and the credit column recalculated to check for agreement before any further processing can take place.\n\nOnce the accounts balance, the accountant makes a number of adjustments and changes the balance amounts of some of the accounts. These adjustments must still obey the double-entry rule: for example, the inventory account and asset account might be changed to bring them into line with the actual numbers counted during a stocktake. At the same time, the expense account associated with use of inventory is adjusted by an equal and opposite amount. Other adjustments such as posting depreciation and prepayments are also done at this time. This results in a listing called the adjusted trial balance. It is the accounts in this list, and their corresponding debit or credit balances, that are used to prepare the financial statements.\n\nFinally financial statements are drawn from the trial balance, which may include:\n\nthe income statement, also known as the statement of financial results, profit and loss account, or P&L\nthe balance sheet, also known as the statement of financial position\nthe cash flow statement\nthe statement of changes in equity, also known as the statement of total recognised gains and losses\nSingle-entry system\nMain article: single-entry bookkeeping\nThe primary bookkeeping record in single-entry bookkeeping is the cash book, which is similar to a checking account register (in UK: cheque account, current account), except all entries are allocated among several categories of income and expense accounts. Separate account records are maintained for petty cash, accounts payable and accounts receivable, and other relevant transactions such as inventory and travel expenses. To save time and avoid the errors of manual calculations, single-entry bookkeeping can be done today with do-it-yourself bookkeeping software.\n\nDouble-entry system\nMain article: double-entry bookkeeping\nA double-entry bookkeeping system is a set of rules for recording financial information in a financial accounting system in which every transaction or event changes at least two different ledger accounts.", {"entities": [["Babylonian", "NORP"], ["2600", "CARDINAL"], ["Mesopotamian", "NORP"], ["as far as 7,000 years", "CARDINAL"], ["Luca Pacioli", "PERSON"], ["1494.[3", "CARDINAL"], ["America", "GPE"], ["daily", "DATE"], ["UK", "GPE"], ["first", "ORDINAL"], ["first", "ORDINAL"], ["each month", "DATE"], ["a month", "DATE"], ["the Sales Journal", "ORG"], ["2", "CARDINAL"], ["three", "CARDINAL"], ["Column One", "PRODUCT"], ["Column Two", "ORG"], ["Column Three", "ORG"], ["two", "CARDINAL"], ["two", "CARDINAL"], ["P&L", "ORG"], ["Main", "PRODUCT"], ["UK", "GPE"], ["today", "DATE"], ["Main", "PRODUCT"], ["at least two", "CARDINAL"]]}], ["A grocery store (AE), grocery shop (BE) or simply grocery[1] is a foodservice retail store that primarily retails a general range of food products,[2] which may be fresh or packaged. In everyday U.S. usage, however, \"grocery store\" is a synonym for supermarket,[3] and is not used to refer to other types of stores that sell groceries. In the UK, shops that sell food are distinguished as grocers[3] or grocery shops (though in everyday use, people usually use either the term \"supermarket\" or a \"corner shop\".)\n\nLarger types of stores that sell groceries, such as supermarkets and hypermarkets, usually stock significant amounts of non-food products, such as clothing and household items. Small grocery stores that sell mainly fruit and vegetables are known as greengrocers (Britain) or produce markets (U.S.), and small grocery stores that predominantly sell prepared food, such as candy and snacks, are known as convenience shops or delicatessens.[citation needed]\n\nDefinition\nThe definition of \"grocery store\" varies; U.S. and Canadian official definitions of \"grocery store\" exclude some businesses that sell groceries, such as convenience stores.\n\nUnited States\nIn the United States,\n\nthe Merriam-Webster Dictionary defines a grocery store as \"a store that sells food and household supplies : supermarket\". In other words, in common U.S. usage, \"grocery store\" is a synonym for supermarket.[4] The Oxford English Dictionary notes that the term \"grocery store\" in American English is often used to mean \"supermarket\".[3]\nthe U.S. and Canadian governments have a wider definition of grocery stores, not limiting them to supermarkets. The category of business (NAICS code 4551) \"Grocery stores\" is defined as \"primarily engaged in retailing a general line of food products\",[2] and the subcategory (NAICS code 455110), \"Supermarkets and Other Grocery (except Convenience) Stores\" is defined as \"establishments generally known as supermarkets and grocery stores, primarily engaged in retailing a general line of food, such as canned and frozen foods; fresh fruits and vegetables; and fresh and prepared meats, fish, and poultry. Included in this industry are delicatessen-type establishments primarily engaged in retailing a general line of food.\nUnited Kingdom\nIn the United Kingdom, terms in common usage include \"supermarket\" (for larger grocery stores), \"corner shop\",[5] \"convenience shop\", or \"grocery\" (meaning a grocery shop) for smaller stores. \"Grocery store\", being a North American term, is not used. The Oxford English Dictionary states that a \"grocery\" is (especially in British English) a shop that sells food and other things used in the home.[3]\n\nThe UK government does not define \"grocery (shop)\" or \"supermarket\" nor a distinction between them, but defines the types of store formats (whether they sell groceries, or otherwise):[6]\n\n\"One-stop shops\" as over 1,400 square metres (15,000 square feet)\n\"Mid-range stores\": between 280 and 1,400 square metres (3,000 and 15,000 square feet), and\n\"Convenience stores\": less than 280 square metres (3,000 square feet)\nIndia\n90% of the 810-billion-dollar Indian food and grocery market sales are at the 12 million small grocery stores, called kirana.[7]\n\nHistory\n", {"entities": [["products,[2", "PRODUCT"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["supermarket,[3", "PRODUCT"], ["UK", "GPE"], ["Britain", "GPE"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["Canadian", "NORP"], ["United States", "GPE"], ["the United States", "GPE"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["American", "NORP"], ["English", "LANGUAGE"], ["U.S.", "GPE"], ["Canadian", "NORP"], ["4551", "DATE"], ["455110", "DATE"], ["Supermarkets and Other Grocery (except Convenience) Stores", "WORK_OF_ART"], ["United Kingdom", "GPE"], ["the United Kingdom", "GPE"], ["North American", "NORP"], ["British", "NORP"], ["English", "LANGUAGE"], ["UK", "GPE"], ["One", "CARDINAL"], ["over 1,400 square metres", "QUANTITY"], ["15,000 square feet", "QUANTITY"], ["between 280 and 1,400", "CARDINAL"], ["3,000 and 15,000 square feet", "QUANTITY"], ["less than 280 square metres", "QUANTITY"], ["3,000 square feet", "QUANTITY"], ["India", "GPE"], ["90%", "PERCENT"], ["810-billion-dollar", "MONEY"], ["Indian", "NORP"], ["12 million", "CARDINAL"]]}], ["House of the dragon is the popular web series in the world", {"entities": [["House", "ORG"]]}], ["Lucky seven is the lucky called in world", {"entities": [["seven", "CARDINAL"]]}], ["one two three going to America", {"entities": [["one", "CARDINAL"], ["two", "CARDINAL"], ["three", "CARDINAL"], ["America", "GPE"]]}]]